An intimate and epic journey into the female experience of war.
For Sama is a documentary, war film directed by Edward Watts.
A love letter from a young mother to her daughter, the film tells the story of Waad al-Kateab’s life through five years of the uprising in
Aleppo, Syria as she falls in love, gets married and gives birth to Sama, all while cataclysmic conflict rises around her.
Her camera captures incredible stories of loss, laughter and survival as Waad wrestles with an impossible choice– whether or not to flee the city to
protect her daughter’s life, when leaving means abandoning the struggle for freedom for which she has already sacrificed so much.
Self, played by Sama Al-Khateab.
Self, played by Hamza Al-Khateab.
Self, played by Waad al-Kateab.
For Sama (Arabic: من أجل سما, romanized: min ʾajl Samā) is a 2019 documentary film produced and
narrated by Waad Al-Kateab, and directed by Waad Al-Kateab and Edward Watts.
The film focuses on Waad Al-Kateab's journey as a
journalist and rebel in the Syrian uprising.
Her husband is Hamza al-Kateab, one of the few doctors left in Aleppo, and they
raise their daughter Sama Al-Kateab during the Syrian Civil War.
The film had its world premiere at the South by Southwest festival on March 11, 2019, where
it won the Documentary Feature Competition's Grand Jury and Audience Awards.
For Sama made history when it was nominated in four categories in the
BAFTA awards, making it the most nominated documentary ever.
It was nominated for the Academy Award for Best
Documentary Feature at the 92nd Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of found footage, woman director, syria.